# Curtis J. Jochen

12628 Copperas, Ln Richmond, Virginia 23236 (406) 471-1679 | Curtis. Jochen@gmail.com

github.com/Cjochen2 | | www.linkedin.com/in/curtisjochen/ | | https://cjochen2.github.io/Portfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Hard-working, driven Software Developer with a focus in Full Stack-Web Development. Extensive experience in client facing roles helping resolve complex problems while being mindful of budget and deadlines. Strong communication and leadership skills from both working in and leading teams through fast pace production driven environments. Obtained University of Richmond's Full Stack Web Development Certification with an A average.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Proficient in HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, VS Code, ¡Query, Bootstrap and MS Office
- · Database MySQL and Mongo DB
- · Node.is Express, Security and Session Storage, User Authentication
- · Effective command of written and verbal communication
- · Experience in client-facing roles
- · Self-motivated professional with strong work ethic and ability to see tasks through to completion

### **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Development Program

Richmond, Virginia

October 2019

University of Richmond

- Built front-end of applications from scratch as well as with ready-made frameworks using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, Handlebars, and React
- · Designed CLI applications utilizing Express, Node, and MySQL
- · Worked in agile groups of 3 to 4 to design and build Full Stack Web Applications utilizing the MERN Stack
- · Designed and Developed full stack single page web applications with RESTful routes and AJAX methods
- · Learned about and worked through the entire development cycle of complex projects in both independent and collaborative settings

### Non-Destructive Testing Certificate of Applied Science

Flathead Valley Community College

Kalispell, Montana December 2014

### **PROJECTS**

### Trivia Game

App: https://cjochen2.github.io/TriviaGame/

Dynamically created trivia game utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery Code: <a href="https://github.com/Cjochen2/TriviaGame">https://github.com/Cjochen2/TriviaGame</a>

- · Application dynamically generates HTML using jQuery
- · Picks 5 random questions from an array and one static question out of an array with multiple choice answers
- · Checks users answers against correct answers and returns a total score output.
- · Application can be reset without refreshing the page

### **GifTastic**

App: https://cjochen2.github.io/GifTastic/

Uses Giphy API call to return 10 GIFs based on the button selected by the user

Code: <a href="https://github.com/Cjochen2/GifTastic">https://github.com/Cjochen2/GifTastic</a>

- · Application makes a dynamic AJAX call to the Giphy API
- · User can create a custom button to return GIFs with
- · Application limits the number of GIFs to 10 and displays each one's rating
- · GIFs render in a still state and can be activated and deactivated on click

## Clicky Game

App: https://cjochen2.github.io/clicky-game/

A memory game using react and state to track user clicked cards and shuffle them Code: https://github.com/Cjochen2/clicky-game

- App is built using React and JSX
- Tracks state of the card the user clicks and shuffles the deck
- If the user clicks the same card twice the app resets state of all cards and resets the score counter

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Applied Technical Services**

Richmond, Virginia January 2015 – Current

Non-Destructive Testing Technician

- · Driving long-term projects to completion while managing strict deadlines and budgets
- · Lead point of contact with the customer, responsible for ensuring overall client satisfaction and clear communication
- · Provide expertise to the client on Applied Technical Services solutions and how to utilize them
- · Directly supervise a 10+ member team, making complex decisions on best utilizing team skills to complete projects under budget
- · Mentor and train junior employees to increase their working knowledge in Advanced Ultrasonic Testing techniques, applications, limitations, material sensitivity and equipment calibration

**Best Buy** Kalispell, Montana

Mobile Sales Rep

November 2013 – December 2014

- · Understanding customer's technical needs and providing them with the appropriate solution
- · Consistently a top performer in a production-oriented environment
- · Leverage analytical and problem-solving skills to proactively improve customer service process

Montana Fire Eureka, Montana May 2013 - November 2014

Wildland Firefighter

- · Focus for extended periods of time to ensure safety in a constantly changing and dangerous environment
- · Work effectively in a team-oriented environment to ensure achievement of daily and overall objectives
- · Maintain an updated knowledge of safety guidelines, firefighting techniques, treatment protocols and quality assurance procedures